Guide to the Ervin S. Hubbard glass plate negative collection, 1895-1901 MS2381
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Geographic locations, 1893-1901; Series 1
  - Illinois, New England, and New York, Series 1 Subseries 2
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1894 September 29; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 8)
      Dredge in Portland Harbor, ME.
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1893 August 25; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 9)
      U.S. Fish Comm. Steamer "Fishhawk" at Calais, ME; 5:30 PM.
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 10)
      Eastport, ME.
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 11)
      Canadian Cutter "Curlew"; Lubec Harbor, ME.
    - "Tomah Stream," Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 12)
      Club House Interior; 22-1
    - "Tomah Stream," Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 13)
      Club House Interior; 22-2
    - "Tomah Stream," Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 14)
      Guide (Geo. Spears) in Canoe; 22-3
    - "Tomah Stream," Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 15)
      Deer; 22
    - "Tomah Stream," Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 16)
      Deer.
  - Maryland, Virginia, and Washington D.C., Series 1 Subseries 3
    This subseries contains glass plate negatives of locations in Maryland, Virginia, and Washington, D.C. Specific locations include: Breton's Bay, MD; Bristol, MD; Ft. Washington, MD; Leonardtown, MD; Lyons Creek, MD; Marshall Hall, MD; Mattawoman, MD; Coan River, VA; Colonial Beach, VA; Kinsale, VA; Mount Vernon, VA; Great Falls Park; Rock Creek Park; downtown Washington, D.C. and the Northwest quadrant; and some unidentified locations. The material in this subseries is dated from 1893-1900, though much of the material remains undated. As a whole, this subseries focuses on topographical images of landscapes, boating scenes, street scenes, prominent Washington buildings, statues and monuments, and the Hubbard family home.
    - Agriculture Building Yard, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 17)
    - Albaugh's Opera House, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 18)
    - Analostan Boat House, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 19)
    - Argyle Mill Road, 1898 August 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 8)
    - Arlington Hotel, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 20)
    - Arlington National Cemetery, 1895 August 27; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 21)
    - Arlington National Cemetery, 1895 August 27; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 22)
    - Arlington National Cemetery, 1895 August 27; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 23)
    - Arlington National Cemetery, 1895 August 27; Series 1, Sub Series 3; Glass plate negative is broken--please handle with care. (Carton 7, Box 26, Item 1)
      Receiving vault
    - Arlington National Cemetery, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 9)
    - Arlington National Cemetery, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3; Glass plate negative is broken--please handle with care. (Carton 7, Box 26, Item 2)
    - Botanical Garden Greenhouse, 1895 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 24)
    - Breton's Bay, Maryland, 1898 July 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 25)
    - Bristol, Maryland, 1898 July 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 26)
    - Bristol, Maryland, 1898 July 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 27)
    - Capitol Building, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 28)
    - Capitol Building, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 29)
    - Chevy Chase Lake, 1899 April 29; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 10)
    - "Churches", 1894 March 14; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 30)
    - "Churches", 1894 March 24; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 1)
    - "Churches", 1894 March 14; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 2)
    - "Churches", 1894 March 12; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 3)
    - "Churches", 1894 March 23; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 4)
    - Coan River, Virginia, 1898 July 26; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 5)
    - Coan River, Virginia, 1898 July 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 6)
    - Coan River, Virginia, 1898 July 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 7)
    - Coan River, Virginia, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 8)
    - Colonial Beach, Virginia, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 9)
    - Congressional Library, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 10)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 11)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 12)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 13)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 14)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 15)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 16)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 17)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 18)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 19)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 20)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 21)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 22)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 23)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 24)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 25)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 26)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 27)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 28)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 29)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 2, Box 6, Item 30)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 1)
      Washington, DC
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 2)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 3)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 4)
    - Coxey's Army Protest, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 5)
    - Davy Burn's Cottage, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 6)
      17th St. between B and C Sts. NW; Washington, DC; "Burn's daughter became the wife of Van Ness who built the house close by."; plate is cracked in corner
    - "Department and Public Buildings", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 7)
      The Capitol
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 4; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 8)
      Treasury building from S.W.; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1895 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 9)
      Treasury Department; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 10)
      Treasury Department.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 11)
      Department of Justice--"Attorney General"; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 4; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 12)
      Pension Office (West End); Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 April 3; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 13)
      Weather Bureau; M St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 4; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 14)
      City Hall and Court House; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 4; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 15)
      Corcoran Art Gallery; 17th & Penn. Ave.; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 4; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 16)
      Corcoran Art Gallery; Lions at entrance; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 17)
      Winder Building; 17th cor. F St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 4; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 18)
      Army Medical Museum; B cor. 7th St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Department and Public Buildings", 1894 March 12; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 19)
      Columbian University; 15th cor. H St.; Washington, DC.
    - Fish Commission, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 7, Box 26, Item 3)
    - Fort Washington, Maryland, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 20)
      No. 54; "George Joyce" off Fort Washington
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 21)
      Aqueduct Bridge; Georgetown, DC.
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 22)
      Rock Crusher; Georgetown, DC.
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 23)
      Hog under bridge; Georgetown, DC.
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 24)
      Canal boat; Georgetown, DC.
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 25)
      Mules toward tow-path; Georgetown, DC.
    - "Georgetown Views", 1893 December; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 26)
      Fire scene etc.; Georgetown, DC.
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 27)
      Fire scene; Georgetown, DC.
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 28)
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 29)
    - "Georgetown Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3; Glass plate negative is broken--please handle with care. (Carton 7, Box 26, Item 4)
      Wharves from Aq. Bridge; Washington, DC; Box 11, No. 2
    - Great Falls Dinner, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 7, Item 30)
      No. 89; Trip of N.N.C.; Velox 1 min 35 sec.
    - Great Falls Hotel, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 11)
    - Great Falls Hotel, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 12)
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 13)
      Lock near Great Falls
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 14)
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 15)
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 16)
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 17)
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 18)
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 19)
    - Great Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 1, Box 21, Item 20)
      (Plate is cracked)
    - Gunston Trip, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 1)
      No. 30; "A Salt Water Mariner"; Don in tender; Velox 40 sec.
    - Gunston Trip, 1898 September 7; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 2)
      "Sylph" off Gunston
    - H Street, 1899 January 14; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 3)
      No. 47; Blizzard, looking on H St.
    - H Street, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 4)
      Rear of Dad's Home
    - "Historical Houses", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 5)
      Key Mansion; Georgetown, DC; Newspaper clipping
    - "Historical Houses", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 6)
      Foxhall House (1795); Georgetown, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 7)
      Van Ness Mansion; Washington, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 8)
      Davy Burns Cottage; 17th St.; Washington, DC; demolished May 1894.
    - "Historical Houses", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 9)
      Davy Burns Cottage; 17th St.; Washington, DC; demolished May 1894,
    - "Historical Houses", 1894 February 16; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 10)
      Tayloe Mansion; Cor. 18th St. - N.Y. Ave.; Washington, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", 1894 March 4; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 11)
      Sec'y James G. Blaine's House; Lafayette Square; Washington, DC; "Mr. Blaine dies in the second story, front room, right hand side. Also an attempt was made in this house to assasanate Sec'y Seward, the night Lincoln was killed."
    - "Historical Houses", 1894 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 12)
      Corcoran House; H St. cor. Conn. Ave.; Washington, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", 1894 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 13)
      Stable of the Corcoran House; H St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 14)
      Decatur Mansion; Home of Gen. Beale; Washington, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", 1894 March 15; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 15)
      War Records Offices; G St. cor. 18th; Washington, DC; "Jefferson Davis while Sec'y of War occupied this house, and left it to go south to join the Confederacy."
    - "Historical Houses", 1894 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 16)
      Grant's headquarters during the war. The tower and the upper story have been added since.; Washington, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", 1895 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 17)
      House in which Abe. Lincoln died; 10th St. N.W.; Washington, DC.
    - "Historical Houses", 1895 March 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 18)
      Baltimore & Potomac R.R. Depot; 6th St. N.W.; Washington, DC; "In the front waiting room of this depot, Pres. J.A. Garfield was shot."
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), 1893 December 25; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 19)
      20th Street Exterior; 716 20th Street; Washington, DC
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), 1893 December 25; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 20)
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 21)
      Backyard corner; 716 20th St.; Washington, DC; 23-5
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 22)
      Flight box: Wachusett Loft; 704 Twentieth Street
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 23)
      Interior view of dining room; 716 20th Street; Washington, DC; 23-3
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 24)
      Interior view of parlor; 716 20th Street; Washington, DC; 23-2
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 25)
      Interior; 20th Street
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 26)
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), 1894 February; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 27)
      "Our Chamber"; 716 20th Street; Washington, DC; 23-4
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 28)
      "Our Front Yard"; #704
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 29)
      "Our Home"; 716 20th Street; Washington, DC; 23-1
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), about 1893; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 8, Item 30)
      Parlor; 716 20th Street; Washington, DC
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 1)
      Spring blossom of Amorphophallus Plant with E.S.H. at side; 704 20th Street.
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 2)
      Spring blossom of Amorphophallus Plant, etc.; Allen Haycock at side; 704 20th Street.
    - Hubbard Home (20th Street), Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 3)
      Summer foliage of Amorphophallus plant, etc.; in front yard; 704 20th St.
    - Kinsale, Virginia, 1898 July 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 4)
      Canning factory
    - Kinsale, Virginia, 1898 July 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 5)
      Cove at Kinsale; West Yeocomico River, VA
    - Kinsale, Virginia, 1898 July 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 6)
      Wharf at Kinsale; West Yeocomico River, VA
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 12; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 7)
      Argentine Republic Legation; 1603 Mass. Ave.; Washington, DC; Newspaper clipping
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 14; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 8)
      Brazilian Legation; 1523 N.H. Ave.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 February 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 9)
      British Legation; Conn. Ave.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 February 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 10)
      Stewart's Castle--Dupont Circle; occupied by Chinese Legation; Washington, DC; Newspaper clipping
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 11)
      German Legation; 1435 Mass. Ave.; Washington, DC; Newspaper clipping
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 12)
      Guatemala Legation; 1755 N. St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 12; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 13)
      Mexican Legation; 1413 I St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 14)
      Netherlands Legation; 1013 15th St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 15)
      Peruvian Legation; 1511 13th St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 31; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 16)
      Russian Legation; I cor. 19th St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 17)
      Sweden & Norway Legation; 2011 Q St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 18)
      Switzerland Legation; 1761 Q. St; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 19)
      The Cosmos Club; Madison Pl. cor. H St.; Washington, DC;"This was the home of Dolly Madison."
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 20)
      The Metropolitan Club; H cor. 17th St.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 March 14; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 21)
      Army and Navy Club; I St. cor. Conn. Ave.; Washington, DC.
    - "Legations and Clubs", 1894 February 18; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 22)
      University Club; Cor. I and 17th St.; Washington, DC.
    - Leonardtown, Maryland, 1898 July 26; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 23)
      6 o'clk A.M.
    - Lyons Creek, Maryland, 1898 July 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 24)
      Silica Mill on Patuxent River
    - Marshall Hall, Maryland, 1900 May 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 25)
      No. 124; Ross Fryer's Boat at Marshall Hall
    - Marshall Hall, Maryland, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 26)
      No. 51; Daisy of Marshall Hall
    - Marshall Hall, Maryland, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 27)
      No. 53; Schooner of Marshall Hall
    - Mattawoman, Maryland, 1900 May 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 28)
      No. 127; "Jenet" and "Culprit" Fay off Mattawoman
    - Mattawoman, Maryland, 1900 May 30; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 29)
      No. 122; Trip with Ross Fryer; C.Y.C. at Mattawoman
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 9, Item 30)
      A Corner of the Old Garden; Newspaper clipping
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 1)
      Barn--Carriage House--Laundry--Smokehouse--Butler's House; Barn built 1733/83 (?)
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 2)
      Barn, Coach House, Laundry, Smokehouse, and Butler's House
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 3)
      Carpenter Shop--Spinning Room
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 4)
      Coach House Interior
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 5)
      East front of Mansion from N.E.
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 6)
      East front of Mansion; No. 1
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 7)
      East front of Mansion; No. 2
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 8)
      East front of Mansion; Newspaper clipping
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 9)
      Greenhouse and servants quarters; Newspaper clipping
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 10)
      Old brick barn; "Erected in 1733 by Lawrence Washington, the brick's being brought from England. Re-roofed in 1875."
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 11)
      Old carriage entrance
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 12)
      Old family vault
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 13)
      Old family vault; "Over the door is a plain granite block, three feet long and two wide, with 'Washington Family' cut into it."
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 14)
      Old servants quarters; "Imperial" Plate
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 15)
      Old servants quarters; Newspaper clipping
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 16)
      The school house; Newspaper clipping
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 17)
      The summer house
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1898 August 22; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 18)
      The sun-dial; "Erected A.D. 1888 by citizens of Rhode Island, in place of the dial which stood here in the time of Washington, and contains this motto, 'Horas non numero nisi serenas.'"
    - Mount Vernon, Virginia, 1895 August 28; Series 1, Sub Series 3 (Carton 3, Box 10, Item 19)
      Sup't house or "Old Stable Kitchen" and gardner's house